Imran Chagani

Personal Details

Occupation: Computer Science Graduate Date of Birth: 26/02/2000

Personal Profile

I am an industrious person, always looking out for a project to undertake and consistently brings a creative mindset to the table. I have gained skills in many different fields from involvement in mechanical and software engineering projects to running a small business model and customer interaction. For this reason I find it very easy to adapt to any task. At the moment I am focused on enhancing my skills in software and programming, and implementing this to my work.

Computing Skills

Programming: Proficient in Java, Ruby on Rails, VBA, Python, HTML, CSS and Javascript **Database Management:** Managed variety of databases (eg. postgreSQL, mySQL) **Development:** Strong at implementing Agile methodology through use of version control, test drive development (TDD) & peer review. Implemented this methodology in many projects. **ERP System:** Extensive experience with a variety of ERP systems. (eg. SAP, Microsoft Dynamics)

Reports: Substantiating whilst authoring and checking technical reports. Able to process data visually in various charts and flow diagrams.

Other: Experience in computer assembly and hardware maintenance. Proficient in high level mathematics.

Work Experience

Software Developer - Masters Speciality Pharma Ltd. - Nov 2021 to present

Data Management Executive - Masters Speciality Pharma Ltd. - June 2021 to Nov 2021 I have been involved in managing Big Data from international entities within the company and creating a custom application alongside a database to increase the sourcing opportunities for the company. I acquired skills in:

- Writing Java algorithms to manipulate and standardise data streamed from excel.
- Independently taught myself VBA to create usable macro enabled excel forms and large search algorithms for the sourcing team to use.
- Communicating with the company's international entities in order to create a scope for the project that would result in a worthwhile application.
- Protecting sensitive data within the company.

Tutor - Explore Learning - October 2020 to May 2021

This role required me teaching Math and English to 4-14 year olds. Being at the forefront of the company and working with such a variety of children has taught me about :

- Upholding company ethos, values and regulations
- Being a role model for the children and the company
- Problem solving and adapting in different scenarios
- Verbally communicating explanations and feedback

Procurement Executive - Masters Speciality Pharma Ltd. - Summer 2020

This role involved acquiring products for a pharmaceutical wholesaler that supplies international customers primarily in the Caribbean and Middle East. Involved in:

- Creating back-to-back purchase orders based on availability and the stock in the warehouse.
- Communicating with international customers to ensure client satisfaction.
- Dealing with controlled substances with high consequential risk.
- Liaising with Quality Assurance to ensure the certification of suppliers.

Sales Team & Office Admin - Techna International - Summer 2019

Working on the sales of a wholesale distributor of Electrical and Mechanical products, involved communicating with customers directly to process their orders. Although not expected, I independently learnt about products supplied by the company to give me further understanding in my role. I also acquired skills:

- Working in a high pressure environment by processing sales orders to meet deadlines.
- Handling enquiries and invoices.
- Understanding business-to-business relations locally and internationally.
- Upholding confidential company information.

General Admissions - West Herts College - Summer 2018

My role required me to advise post GCSE students of potential career paths and enroll them to the college. Aspects of the job included :

- Working with my team to ensure all students were being catered to in the high demanding environments.
- Assessing strengths, weaknesses and interests for a range of students and communicating their prospects.
- Remaining vigilant and patient in the face of challenging clients situations.

Education

Royal Holloway University of London, Bsc of Computer Science

2018 - 2021 : Graduated with a First Class Honors, BSc

Watford Grammar Sixth Form, Sep 2016 - July 2018, A Levels

Watford Grammar School for Boys, GCSE

Transport

I have my own car if required and also able to take public transport if needed.

Interests

I really enjoy working mechanically with cars and bikes. I try to build fun and unique projects to test my abilities. I also am a great advocate in staying fit and I find unwinding in the gym helpful.

Languages

English: Fluent French: Semi-fluent